Guide to the Frederick B. Nightingale stereographs of China, 1920-1921 RL.10984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Frederick B. Nightingale stereographs of China
1920-1921
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.10984
0.2 Linear Feet 1 box
Collection of 143 stereographic images of areas in southeastern China, taken by an amateur photographer and American lighting engineer Frederick B. Nightingale from 1920 to 1921, while he traveled on business as a representative of General Electric. Nightingale's photographs are of value not only for the image content, which includes street scenes, vendors, modes of transportation, shrines, temples, pagodas, monasteries, towers, and landscapes, but also for his lengthy contextual commentary written on the back of each card. The majority of the images were taken in Hangzhou (referred to as Hangchow), Suzhou (Soochow), Mount Putuo island (Pu-tu), and Shanghai, China, but there are also a few images from other cities (Ningbo, Chang'an, and Harinen?), and a set of 11 images were taken in Japan. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Collection of 143 stereographic images of areas in southeastern China, taken by amateur photographer and American lighting engineer Frederick B. (F.B.) Nightingale from 1920 to 1921 while he traveled on business as a representative of General Electric. Nightingale's collection is of value not only for the image content, which includes many street scenes with individuals in addition to well-known sites and landscapes, but also for his lengthy captions on the back of each card, commenting on food customs, architecture, folklore, commerce, and religious beliefs and practices, as seen from a Westerner's perspective.
The majority of the images were taken in Suzhou (referred to in captions as Soochow, 55 images), Hangzhou (Hangchow, 44), Mount Putuo Island (Pu-tu, 14), and Shanghai, China (13), but there are also a few photographs from other cities (Chang'an, Ningbo, Harinen?), and a set of 11 images taken in Japan. There is also one photograph of overgrown land on Nightingale's Pasadena, California property called "Palawoo." Several images feature Nightingale, and one shows the porter carrying his camera equipment. The majority of the images are crisp with little fading. A few are stamped with small identification numbers.
Subjects include numerous temples, pagodas, monasteries, monuments, tombs, and other historic sites, some of which no longer exist. Nightingale was able to capture some images of temple interiors, and he often noted which religious sites allowed entry to women. There are many photos of street life, river traffic, modes of transportation, and Chinese vendors and pedestrians going about their daily business.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Arrangement
The stereograph cards are organized by geographic location in alphabetical order, according to places indicated in original captions.
Biographical Note
Frederick B. Nightingale (F.B.) was born in 1885 and died in the 1950s. He worked in sales for General Electric until the 1940s, when he founded his own lighting company, Kim Lighting, and became a local celebrity in 1928 when he erected the giant "Star of Palawoo" above his Pasadena property in the Altadena hills in California.
Provenance
The F. B. Nightingale stereographs of China were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in February 2014.
China -- Pictorial works; Shanghai (China) -- Pictorial works; Japan -- Pictorial works; China -- History -- Republic, 1912-1949 -- Pictorial works; China -- Social life and customs; Documentary Photography -- China; China -- Description and travel -- 18th Century; China -- History -- 1912-1928; Putuo Shan Island (China) -- Pictorial works; Suzhou (Jiangsu Sheng, China) -- Pictorial works; Hangzhou (China) -- Pictorial works; Black-and-white photographs; Stereographs; China -- Religious life and customs; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Changan [Xi'an], 2 items
  - The Post Boat, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Aboard the Post Boat, 1920 (Box 1)
- Hangchow [Hangzhou], 44 items
  - "The Bore" No. 2, 1920 (Box 1)
  - "The Bore" No. 4, 1920 (Box 1)
  - "The Bore" No. 6, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Canal Life, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Monastery of Buddha's Image (Ta-Hsiang Szu), 1921 (Box 1)
  - Typical Canal scene, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Entrance to "Cave of the Morning Mist and Sunset Glow", 1921 (Box 1)
  - Typical scene at a City Gate, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Dragon Well Valley "Lung-Ching", 1921 (Box 1)
  - Drying Rice, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Gem Spring of the Dancing Fish, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Island of the Three Pools and Moon's Reflection, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Mahommedan Mosque, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Arch-way, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Stairway to the Monastery of Buddhas Image, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Cave of the Morning Mist and Sunset Glow, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Within the Monastery of Buddhas Image (Ta-Hsiang Szu), 1921 (Box 1)
  - Mulberry Trees, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Native Method of Well Drilling, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Across the rice fields to the Hills at Za-kow, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Looking Out - "Cave of the Morning Mist and Sunset Glow", 1921 (Box 1)
  - Stone House Cave (Shih-Wu-Tung), 1921 (Box 1)
  - A Temple Shrine - City Hill, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Temple of North High Peak (Pei-Kao-Feng), 1921 (Box 1)
  - Six Harmony Pagoda at Za-Kou, 1921 (Box 1, Image 820)
  - Six Harmony Pagoda at Za-Kou, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Six Harmony Pagoda (Liu-Ho-T'a) at Za-Kou, 1921 (Box 1, Image 819)
  - Looking Over the Chien T'ang River, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Within a Way-side Shrine (Tao Kuang), 1921 (Box 1)
  - Monastery of Concentrated Light, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Monastery of Ling Yin, 1920 (Box 1)
  - At Ling Yin, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Pilgrims Arriving at Ling Yin, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Another View of the 500 Hohan - at Ling Yin Monastery, 1921 (Box 1)
  - A Name-less Temple, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Within the "Monastery of Precious Completion" (Pao-Cheng Szu), 1921 (Box 1)
  - Looking to the Valley - from "Monastery of Concentrated Light", 1921 (Box 1)
  - Entrance - "Monastery of the Rule of Peace" (Li-An-Szu), 1921 (Box 1)
  - Monastery of Ling Yin "The Spirits Retreat", 1921 (Box 1, Image 796)
  - Monastery of Ling Yin - "The Spirits Retreat", 1921 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Duplicate of 796 but not marked with image number.
  - Snake Charmers at Ling Yin, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Spirits Retreat [rock carvings with Sanskrit writing], 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Spirits Retreat, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Spirits Retreat, 1921 (Box 1)
- Harinen (?), 2 items
  - Native Street Scene, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A City Gate, 1920 (Box 1)
- Ningpo [Ningbo], 1 item
  - An Old Doctor at the Temple, 1921 (Box 1)
- Palawoo (Pasadena, California), 1 item
  - The Jungle, 1921 (Box 1, Image 41)
- Pu-tu [Mount Putuo Island], 14 items
  - Out on "Chien-pu" (Thousand Paces) Beach, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Pai-hua Mountain, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Climbing "Pai-hua" Mountain, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Arch to the Monastery, 1920 (Box 1)
  - An Ancient Tomb, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Courtyard in One of the Temples, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Lily Sea from "Buddha Top" Mountain, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Nan Tien Man (Gate to South Heaven), 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Princes Tower, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Out for a "Sampan" Ride on the "Lily Sea", 1920 (Box 1)
  - A forest at the Base of Pai-hua Mountain, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The "Ta Yuan Tung" Temple of the "Pu-chi Monastery", 1920 (Box 1)
  - Within the "Ta Yuan Tung" Temple of the "Pu-chi Monastery", 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Rest Spot on the way to "Miao Chuang", 1920 (Box 1)
- Shanghai, 13 items
  - Off For Work [H.B. Lane and F.B. Nightingale], 1920 (Box 1)
  - Sampans, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Three Arch Stone Bridge, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Chow --!, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Half a Sail -- is Better than None, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The House Boat "Danica" & its Happy Family, 1921 (Box 1)
    Names of five individuals listed on back of card: Frances Widner, Dara [Deva?] Shelley, Josephine Rare [Rave?], Mrs. Hubbard, and Hugh Creighton.
  - Native Craft Sailing by, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Pumpkins -- Coming to Market, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Along Siccawei Creek, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Restful Spot, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Chinese Junk, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Five Magicians, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Rustic Spot in the French Park, 1920 (Box 1)
- Soochow [Suzhou], 55 items
  - One Way to Travel, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Water Way - In a Poor Section, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Arch Bridge, 1921 (Box 1)
  - A Beggar-man on a Bridge, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Acrobats and Fencers - City Temple Grounds, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Frying Rice Cakes, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Twin Pagodas, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Ink Pagoda, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Methusela - Old South Gate Pagoda, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Twin Pagodas, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Ink Pagoda, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Twin Pagodas, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Great Pagoda, 1920 (Box 1)
  - An Ancestral Tablet, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Twin Pagodas, 1921 (Box 1)
  - City Temple, 1921 (Box 1)
  - A Canal Bridge, 1921 (Box 1)
  - A City Water Gate, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Along a Canal, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Stone Map of Soochow, Confucian Temple, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Stone Carving, 1920 (Box 1)
  - South Gate Pagoda, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Three Arch Bridge - Confucian Temple, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Astronomical Tablet - Confucian Temple, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Confucian Temple Gateway, 1921 (Box 1)
  - The Confucian Temple, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Confucian Temple, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Great Pagoda, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Shrine Within the Great Pagoda, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Soochow China, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Stone Carving - Close View, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Tablet in the Imperial Gardens, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Central Shrine in the Temple, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Stone House Cave (Shih-Wu-Tung), 1921 (Box 1)
  - Along the Canal, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Liu Yuen Gardens, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Liu Yuen Gardens, 1921 (Box 1)
  - A Lotus Pool - "Liu Yuen", 1920 (Box 1)
  - Through a Window at Liu Yuen Gardens, 1921 (Box 1)
  - A Doorway - Liu Gardens, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Imperial Gardens, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Pavilion - Imperial Gardens, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Imperial Garden, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Water Scene Imperial Gardens, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Pavilion & Walks at Liu Yuen, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Railway Hotel, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Corner of the Railway Hotel, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A Rockery at West Gardens, 1920 (Box 1)
  - A "Love Boat" on the Grand Canal, 1920 (Box 1)
  - The Thousand Arm Buddha, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Archway and Temple Entrance, 1921 (Box 1)
  - A Isle of Idols, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Out-side the City Wall, 1921 (Box 1)
  - City Temple Grounds, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Nodding Rock on Tiger Hill, 1920 (Box 1)
- Japan, 11 items
  - The Temple of Gongen, 1921 (Box 1, Image 134)
  - Pilgrims who Came to Worship at the Shrine, 1921 (Box 1, Image 150)
  - Yomeimon Gate, 1921 (Box 1, Image 152)
  - The Inner "Holy of Holies", 1921 (Box 1, Image 158)
  - A Silent Pool in the Forest at Nikko, 1921 (Box 1, Image 168)
  - Another View in the Park at Nikko, 1921 (Box 1, Image 170)
  - Garden and Bridge at the Fugi Hotel, 1921 (Box 1, Image 139)
  - In the Forest of Cryptomeria Trees, 1921 (Box 1, Image 172)
  - High Tension and Slow Speed, 1921 (Box 1, Image 192)
    "A high-voltage transformer being drawn by bull & cart in Tokyo."
  - A View in the Park at Tokyo, 1921 (Box 1, Image 251)
  - Feeding the Doves at Maruyama Park, 1921 (Box 1, Image 209)